

joshua.a.abrams@gmail.com
(847) 636-6440
https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-a-abrams/
http://uxdesignportfol.io
Chicago, IL

I'm so glad that I have found the beautiful cross-section between tech and design. Since my childhood days on Geocities, I've been designing and coding websites for the world to see and I'm eager to bring to bring my tech experience and design skills to the table in my new career. I am proud to be creating solutions in my field and intend to do so for many years to come.

SKILLS

Design Tools: Sketch, Invision, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Programming Languages: Javascript, C#, Ruby

Version Control: Git, TFS

Web Technologies: ASP.net MVC, Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS, JSON, XML

Industries: Finance, Healthcare, Warehouse Logistics, Medicine, Law

PROJECTS

Transit Talk (Ongoing)

Working as a UX designer on a crowd-sourced issue reporting platform for public transit systems.

Bartleby's Ice Cream Cakes

Upgraded, redesigned, and refined an e-commerce platform for a local, woman-owned food startup.

Summer CSO

Designed a platform for the Chicago Symphony Orchestra to help attract Millenial audiences. This was a mock client project for General Assembly.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

UX Design Fellow

July 2019 - September 2019

Worked in solo and group capacities to deliver high quality research and design for web and mobile applications. Exercised Agile and Waterfall methodologies in a fast paced, quickly changing environment. Worked with cutting edge UX design strategies and technologies.

SPR Consulting

April 2016 - February 2019

Software Engineering Consultant

Developed complex web solutions in a professional technical consulting environment. Responsible for building and maintaining client application solutions.

bswift

May 2016 - November 2019

Fulfillment Analyst

Emphasized client and broker related fulfillment duties. Responsibilities include maintaining contact with clients and brokers regarding company services and coordinating routine bulk mailings as well as routine enrollment changes. Coordinated large mailings to various clients on a regular basis. Handled large scale spreadsheet data integrity checks with the use of macros and pivot tables.

EDUCATION

General Assembly - Chicago, IL
UX Design Immersive
Dev Bootcamp - Chicago, IL
Web Development Immersive

July 2019 - September 2019

September 2019 - January 2019